- 我们首先为什么要研究人工智能？
- Why are we working on AI in the first place?
字幕：@马小红里奥
我只是随意选择贾里德。
I'm just gonna arbitrarily pick Jared.
你为什么要做人工智能？
Why are you doing AI at all?
- 我的意思是，我研究物理学很长时间了
- I mean  I was working on physics for a long time
我感到无聊，
and I got bored
我想和更多的朋友一起出去玩
and I wanted to hang out with more of my friends
所以是的。
so yeah.
- 是的，我以为是达里奥向你推销的。
- Yeah  I thought Dario pitched you on it.
- 我认为我在任何时候都没有明确向你推销过。
- I don't think I explicitly pitched you at any point.
我只是向你们展示了人工智能模型的结果
I just kind of  like  showed you results of  like  AI models
然后试图表明这一点，比如，
and then was trying to make the point that  like
它们非常普遍，不仅仅适用于一件事
they're very general and they don't only apply to one thing
然后就在某个时刻，
and then just at some point
在我向你展示了足够多的内容之后，你会说，
after I showed you enough of them  you were like
“哦，是啊，看来是这样啊。”
"Oh yeah  that seems like it's right."
- 你之前当教授多久了？
- How long had you been a professor before?
比如，你什么时候开始的？
Like  when you started?
- 我想大概有六年左右。
- I think like six years or so.
我想我帮助招募了萨姆。
I think I helped recruit Sam.
- 我和你谈过，你说，
- I talked to you and you were like
“我想我在这里创造了一个很好的泡沫——”
"I think I've created a good bubble here-"
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- “就像我的目标是让汤姆回来一样。”
- "And like my goal is to get Tom to come back."
那行得通。
That worked.
- 你是通过 Google 认识每个人的吗
- And did you meet everyone through Google
当你在做可解释性的事情时，克里斯？
when you were doing the interpretability stuff  Chris?
- 不。
- No.
所以我猜
So I guess
其实我19岁的时候就认识了一群你们
I actually met a bunch of you when I was 19
我正在拜访--哦，是吗？
and I was visiting- - Oh yeah?
- 第一次来到湾区。
- In the Bay Area for the first time.
所以我想我当时就认识了达里奥和贾里德，
So I guess I met Dario and Jared then
我猜他们是博士后
and I guess they were postdocs
我当时觉得这很酷。
which I thought was very cool at the time.
然后我在 Google Brain 工作，Dario 加入了
And then I was working at Google Brain and Dario joined
事实上，我们并肩坐了一会儿。
and we sat side by side  actually  for a while.
我们的桌子并排，
We had desks beside each other
我也和汤姆一起在那里工作。
and I worked with Tom there as well.
然后，当然，
And then  of course
当我去 OpenAI 的时候，我和你们所有人一起工作。
I got to work with all of you at OpenAI when I went there.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 所以我想我认识你们很多人是因为，
- So I guess I've known a lot of you for  like
十多年了，这有点疯狂。
more than a decade  which is kind of wild.
- 如果我没记错的话
- If I remember correctly
2015 年，当我参加你参加的一个会议时，我认识了达里奥
I met Dario in 2015 when I went to a conference you were at
我试图采访你，谷歌公关说
and I tried to interview you and Google PR said
我会阅读你所有的研究论文
I would've read all of your research papers
你需要-
that you needed to-
- 呃，是的，我想我正在写
- Uh  yeah  I think I was writing
《人工智能安全的具体问题》
"Concrete problems in AI safety"
当我在谷歌的时候。
when I was at Google.
- 我认为你写了一个关于那篇论文的故事。
- I think you wrote a story about that paper.
- 我做到了。
- I did.
- 我记得在我开始和你一起工作之前，
- I remember right before I started working with you
我想你邀请我去办公室
I think you invited me to the office
我喜欢来聊天
and I got to like come chat
就像告诉我有关人工智能的一切一样。
and just like tell me everything about AI.
你喜欢解释，
And you like explained
我记得后来是这样的，
I remember afterwards being like
“哦，我想这东西是
"Oh  I guess this stuff is
比我意识到的要严重得多。
much more serious than I realized.
而你就像，
And you were  like
可能解释了计算的大问题
probably explaining the big blob of compute
和参数计数一样
and like parameter counting
以及大脑中有多少神经元等等。
and how many neurons are in the brain and everything.
- 我觉得达里奥经常对人们产生这种影响；
- And I feel like Dario often has that effect on people;
“这比我意识到的要严重得多。”
"This is much more serious than I realized."
- 是的，我是带来好消息的人。
- Yeah  I'm the bringer of happy tidings.
- 但我记得我们在 OpenAI 的时候
- But I remember when we were at OpenAI
当有缩放定律的时候
when there was the scaling law stuff
并让事情变得更大
and just making things bigger
并开始感觉它正在发挥作用，
and it started to feel like it was working
然后它继续奇怪地工作
and then it kind of kept on eerily working
在许多不同的项目中，
on a bunch of different projects
我想这就是我们所有人的结局
which I think is how we all ended up
密切合作，
working closely together
因为这是第一个 GPT-2
'cause it was first GPT-2
然后是缩放法则和 GPT-3，我们最终得到了——
and then scaling laws and GPT-3 and we ended up-
- 是的，我们是一群人
- Yeah  we were the blob of people
这让一切顺利进行。 - 是的。
that were making things work. - Yeah.
- 这是正确的。
- That's right.
- 我认为我们也对安全感到兴奋，
- I think we're also excited about safety
因为在那个时代有这样一种想法
'cause in that era there was sort of this idea that
人工智能将变得非常强大
AI would become very powerful
但是，就像，可能不理解人类价值观
but  like  potentially not understand human values
甚至无法与我们沟通。
or not even be able to communicate with us.
所以我想我们都非常兴奋
And so I think we were all pretty excited about
语言模型作为一种保证的方式
language models as a way to kind of guarantee
人工智能系统必须理解
that AI systems would have to understand
一种隐性知识——
kind of implicit knowledge that-
- 以及来自语言模型之上的人类反馈的强化学习，
- And RL from human feedback on top of language models
这就是扩大这些模型规模的全部原因
which was the whole reason for scaling these models up
是不是，你知道，模型不够智能
was that  you know  the models weren't smart enough
在此基础上进行 RLHF，
to do RLHF on top of
所以这就是一种交织在一起的
so that's the kind of intertwinement of
我们知道，模型的安全性和扩展性，
safety and scaling of the models that we  you know
今天依然相信。
still believe in today.
- 是的，我认为还有一个类似的因素
- Yeah  I think there was also an element of like
扩展工作是作为安全团队的一部分完成的
the scaling work was done as part of the safety team
那，你知道 - 嗯嗯。
that  you know- - Mm-hmm.
- Dario 开始在 OpenAI 工作，
- Dario started at OpenAI
因为我们认为预测人工智能趋势
because we thought that forecasting AI trends
能够让我们认真对待很重要
was important to be able to have us taken seriously
并认真对待安全问题。
and take safety seriously as a problem.
- 正确的。
- Correct.
- 是的，我们采取了，
- Yeah  and we took
我记得在英国的某个机场
I remember being in some airport in England
从 GPT-2 中采样并用它来撰写假新闻文章
sampling from GPT-2 and using it to write fake news articles
和偷懒的达里奥，就像，
and Slacking Dario and being like
“哦，这个东西确实有效。
"Oh  this stuff actually works.
它可能有，比如，
It might have  like
巨大的政策影响。”
huge policy implications."
我想达里奥说了类似“是的”的话。
I think Dario said something like  "Yes."
他的典型方式。
His typical way.
但后来我们做了很多工作
But then we worked on that a bunch
以及发布的东西，这有点疯狂。
as well as the release stuff  which was kind of wild.
- 是的，我记得发布的内容。
- Yeah  I remember the release stuff.
我想那是我们第一次开始合作的时候。
I think that was when we first started working together.
- 是的。 -那是一段有趣的时光。
- Yeah. - That was a fun time.
- 是的。 - GPT-2 发射。
- Yes. - The GPT-2 launch.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
但我认为这对我们有好处，因为我们做了一种
But I think it was good for us 'cause we did a kind of
有点奇怪，完全以安全为导向的东西，
slightly strange  safety-oriented thing altogether
然后我们最终做了 Anthropic，
and then we ended up doing Anthropic
这是一个更大的，有点奇怪的，
which is a much larger  slightly strange
安全为本——
safety-oriented thing-
- 这是正确的。 - 一起。
- That's right. - Together.
- 所以我想就像回到具体问题一样，
- So I guess just like going back to the concrete problems
因为我记得，
'cause I remember
所以我在 2016 年加入了 OpenAI，
so I joined OpenAI in like 2016
比如前 20 名员工之一或其他什么人
like one of the first 20 employees or whatever
和你在一起，达里奥，
with you  Dario
我记得当时
and I remember at that time
人工智能安全的具体问题
the concrete problems in AI safety
看起来就像第一个主流人工智能安全——
seemed like it was like the first mainstream AI safety-
- 是的。 - 我猜是纸？
- Yes. - Paper  I guess?
我真的不知道我是否曾问过你这个故事是什么
I don't really know if I ever asked you what the story was
这是怎么发生的。
for how that came about.
- 克里斯知道这个故事，因为他参与其中。
- Chris knows the story  'cause he was involved in it.
我想，你知道，我们都曾在谷歌工作。
I think  you know  we were both at Google.
我忘记了我正在做的其他项目，
I forget what other project I was working on
但就像很多事情一样，
but like with many things
这是我试图拖延的事情
it was my attempt to kind of procrastinate from
无论我正在从事的其他项目
whatever other project I was working on
我现在已经
that I've now
完全忘记那是什么了。
completely forgotten what it was.
但我认为这就像克里斯和我决定写下来
But I think it was like Chris and I decided to write down
人工智能安全方面有哪些悬而未决的问题，
what are some open problems in terms of AI safety
还有你常说的AI安全
and also AI safety you usually talked about
以这种深奥、抽象的方式。
in this very kind of abstruse  abstract way.
我们能否将其融入到机器学习中
Can we kind of ground it in the ML
当时正在发生什么？
that was going on at the time?
我的意思是，现在已经过去了，你知道，六七年了
I mean  now there's been  like  you know  six  seven years
以这种方式进行工作，
of work in that vein
但这在当时几乎是一个奇怪的想法。
but it was almost a strange idea at the time.
- 是的，我认为在某种程度上它几乎是
- Yeah  I think there's a way in which it was almost a
一种政治项目，当时，
kind of political project  where at the time
很多人没有认真对待安全。
a lot of people didn't take safety seriously.
所以我认为有这样一个目标
So I think that there was sort of this goal
整理问题清单
to collate a list of problems
这类人同意是有道理的，
that sort of people agreed were reasonable
通常已经存在于文学中，
often already existed in literature
然后让一群来自不同机构的人
and then get a bunch of people across different institutions
谁是可信的作者。
who are credible to be authors.
就像，我记得我有这么长一段时间
And like  I remember I had this whole long period
我刚刚与 Brain 的 20 名不同研究人员进行了交谈
where I just talked to 20 different researchers at Brain
为发表论文建立支持。
to build support for publishing the paper.
就像在某些方面，
Like in some ways
如果你从问题的角度来看
if you look at it in terms of the problems
以及很多强调的事情，
and a lot of things that emphasized
我认为，你知道，并没有那么好
I think it  you know  hasn't held up that well
因为它是，你知道，
in that it's  you know
我认为这并不是真正正确的问题，
I think it's not really the right problems
但我认为如果你把它看作是
but I think if you sort of see it instead as
建立共识的活动，
a consensus-building exercise
这里有一些真实的东西
that there's something here that is real
这值得认真对待
and that is worth taking seriously
那是一个非常重要的时刻。
then it was a pretty important moment.
- 我的意思是，你最终会进入这个非常奇怪的科幻世界
- I mean  you end up in this really weird sci-fi world
我记得在《人择》一开始的时候，
where I remember at the start of Anthropic
我们正在谈论宪法人工智能
we were talking about constitutional AI
我想贾里德说，
and I think Jared said
“哦，我们只是要写一部宪法
"Oh  we're just gonna write a constitution
对于语言模型
for a language model
这将改变它的所有行为。”
and that'll change all of its behavior."
我记得这听起来非常疯狂
And I remember that sounded incredibly crazy
当时，
at the time
但你们为什么认为这会起作用？
but why did you guys think that was gonna work?
因为我记得那是最早的一个，就像，
Because I remember that was one of the first early  like
我们在公司有重大的研究想法。
big research ideas we had at the company.
- 是的，我的意思是，
- Yeah  I mean
我想达里奥和我已经讨论了一段时间。
I think Dario and I had talked about it for a while.
我想我想的是简单的事情
I guess I think simple things
在人工智能领域工作得非常非常好。
just work really  really well in AI.
就这样，我认为第一个版本
And so like  I think the first versions of that
相当复杂，
were quite complicated
但后来我们有点想削减成，比如，
but then we kind of like whittled away into  like
只需利用人工智能系统擅长的事实
just use the fact that AI systems are good at
解决多项选择题考试
solving multiple choice exams
并给他们一个提示，告诉他们
and give them a prompt that tells them
他们正在寻找什么，而且有很多
what they're looking for and that was kind of a lot of
我们需要什么。
what we needed.
- 然后我们就可以写下这些原则。
- And then we were able to just write down these principles.
- 我的意思是，它可以追溯到计算的大块
- I mean  it goes back to  like  the big blob of compute
或惨痛的教训或缩放假设。
or the bitter lesson or the scaling hypothesis.
如果你能识别的话，你就知道，
If you can identify  you know
你可以提供人工智能数据的东西
something that you can give the AI data for
这是一个明确的目标
and that's kind of a clear target
你会得到它来做到这一点。
you'll get it to do it.
就像这是这组说明，
So like here's this set of instructions
这是这套原则。
here's this set of principles.
AI语言模型可以阅读那套原则
AI language models can like read that set of principles
他们可以将其与行为进行比较
and they can compare it to the behavior
他们自己正在从事的事情。
that they themselves are engaging in.
就像你已经有了训练目标一样，
And so like you've got your training target there
所以一旦你知道了
so once you know that
我认为我的观点和贾里德的观点是
I think my view and Jared's view is
有一种方法可以让它发挥作用；
there's a way to get it to work;
你只需要摆弄足够的细节即可。
you just have to fiddle with enough of the details.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
我觉得这对我来说总是很奇怪
I think it was always weird for me
尤其是在这些早期时代，
especially in these early eras
因为就像我以前学的是物理，后来又从物理专业毕业，
'cause like I was in physics and then coming from physics
我想现在我们忘记了这一点
and I think now we forget about this
因为每个人都对人工智能感到兴奋
'cause everyone's excited about AI
但就像，我记得和达里奥谈论过
but like  I remember talking to Dario about
具体问题和其他事情，
concrete problems and other things
我刚刚感觉到人工智能研究人员
and I just got the sense that AI researchers
心理受到了非常非常大的伤害
were very  very kind of psychologically damaged
人工智能寒冬来临之际
by the AI winter
他们只是觉得
where they just kind of felt like
有真正雄心勃勃的想法或雄心勃勃的愿景
having really ambitious ideas or ambitious visions
是非常不被允许的。
was  like  very disallowed.
这就是我想象的样子
And that's kind of how I imagine it was
在谈论安全方面。
in terms of talking about safety.
为了关心安全，
In order to care about safety
你必须相信人工智能系统实际上可以
you have to believe that AI systems could actually be
真的很强大而且很有用，
really powerful and really useful
我认为有某种禁令
and I think that there was kind of a prohibition
反对野心勃勃。
against being ambitious.
- 我认为
- And I think
好处之一就是物理学家非常傲慢
one of the benefits is that physicists are very arrogant
所以他们不断地
and so they're constantly
做真正雄心勃勃的事情
doing really ambitious things
并从宏伟的计划中谈论事情，
and talking about things in terms of grand schemes
所以-
and so-
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 我的意思是，我认为这绝对是真的。
- I mean  I think that's definitely true.
就像我记得的 2014 年，
Like I remember in 2014
就好像，我不知道，
it was like there were just like  I don't know
只是有些话不能说，对吧？
there were just some things you couldn't say  right?
但我实际上认为这是问题的延伸
But I actually think it was kind of an extension of problems
学术界普遍存在的现象，
that exist across academia
除了理论物理之外，
other than maybe theoretical physics
他们已经进化成
where they've kind of evolved into
由于多种原因，这些机构非常厌恶风险。
very risk-averse institutions for a number of reasons.
甚至人工智能的工业部分
And even the industrial parts of AI
已经有种移植或分叉解除了这种心态。
had kind of transplanted or fork lifted that mentality.
这花了很长时间。
And it took a long time.
我认为直到 2022 年
I think it took it until like 2022
摆脱这种心态。
to get out of that mentality.
- 有一个奇怪的事情，
- There's a weird thing about like
保守和尊重意味着什么
what does it mean to be conservative and respectful
你可能会想，
where you might think like
你可以拥有的一个版本是
one version you could have is that
保守意味着冒险
what it means to be conservative is to take the risks
或者你正在做的事情的潜在危害
or the potential harms of what you're doing
真的很认真并担心这一点。
really seriously and worry about that.
但另一种保守主义是这样的，
But another kind of conservatism is to be like
“啊，你知道，把一个想法看得太认真了
"Ah  you know  taking an idea too seriously
并相信它可能会成功
and believing that it might succeed
有点像科学上的傲慢。”
is sort of like scientific arrogance."
所以我认为有两种不同的类型
And so I think there's like kind of two different kinds of
保守或谨慎，
conservatism or caution
我认为我们有点像在一个政权中
and I think we were sort of in a regime
那是被那个人非常控制的。
that was very controlled by that one.
我的意思是，你从历史的角度来看，对吗？
I mean  you see it historically  right?
就像你看看 1939 年的早期讨论一样
Like if you look at the early discussions in 1939
你知道，从事核物理学的人们之间
between  you know  people involved in nuclear physics
关于核弹是什么
about what the nuclear bombs were
有点严重的担忧。
sort of a serious concern.
你看到完全相同的东西
You see exactly the same thing
费米抵制这些想法，
with Fermi resisting these ideas
因为这看起来有点疯狂。
because it just seemed kind of like a crazy thing.
还有其他人，比如西拉德或泰勒，
And other people  like Szilard or Teller
认真对待这些想法
taking the ideas seriously
因为他们担心风险。
because they were worried about the risks.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
也许是最深刻的教训
Perhaps the deepest lesson
我在过去10年里学到的
that I've learned in the last 10 years
也许，你知道，
and probably  you know
你们所有人也都学到了某种形式，
all of you have learned some form of it as well
是否可以有这种表面上的共识，
is there can be this kind of seeming consensus
这些大家都知道的事情
these things that kind of everyone knows
那个，我不知道，
that  I don't know
看起来有点明智，看起来像是常识，
seem sort of wise  seem like they're common sense
但实际上，它们只是一种羊群行为
but really  they're just kind of herding behavior
伪装成成熟和老练。
masquerading as maturity and sophistication.
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 当你看到共识可以在一夜之间改变时 -
- And when you've seen the consensus can change overnight-
当你看到这样的事情发生很多次时，
And when you've seen it happen a number of times
你怀疑但你并没有真正下注
you suspected but you didn't really bet on it
你会说，“天啊，我有点想，
and you're like  "Oh man  I kind of thought this
但我知道什么？”
but what do I know?"
你知道，“我怎么可能是对的
You know  "How how can I be right
而这些人都错了？”
and all these people are wrong?"
你看到几次，然后你就开始说，
You see that a few times  then you just start saying
“不，这就是我们要做的赌注。
"Nope  this is the bet we're gonna make.
我不确定我们是否正确
I don't know for sure if we're right
但就像，忽略所有其他事情，看着它发生，
but like  just ignore all this other stuff  see it happen
而且，我不知道，即使你有 50% 的时间是对的
and  I don't know  even if you're right 50% of the time
50% 的时间是正确的贡献很大，”对吗？
being right 50% of the time contributes so much " right?
你加了这么多
You're adding so much
那不是由其他人添加的。
that is not being added by anyone else.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 感觉这就是我们今天的处境
- And it feels like that's where we are today
加上一些安全的东西，
with some safety stuff
人们一致认为
where there's like a consensus view that
很多安全问题都是不寻常的
a lot of this safety stuff is unusual
或者不会自然地脱离技术。
or doesn't naturally fall out of the technology.
然后在 Anthropic，我们进行所有这些研究
And then at Anthropic  we do all of this research
奇怪的安全错位问题在哪里
where weird safety misalignment problems
作为我们正在构建的技术的自然红利，
fall out as a natural dividend of the tech we're building
所以感觉就像我们身处其中
so it feels like we're in that
现在的观点是相反的。
counter-consensus view right now.
- 但我觉得这种情况已经过去了，
- But I feel like that has been shifting over the past
即使只是像18-
even just like 18-
-我们一直在帮助转变-
- We've been helping to shift-
- 我们确实一直在提供帮助。
- We've definitely been helping.
- 不，我是说- - 是的。
- No  I mean- - Yeah.
- 通过出版和研究。
- By publishing and doing research.
- 不断出版。 - 这种恒定的力量。
- Constant publishing. - This constant force.
是的。 - 但我也认为，只是，
Yeah. - But I also think  just
围绕人工智能的世界情绪发生了巨大的变化，
world sentiment around AI has shifted really dramatically
而且，你知道，
and  you know
这在我们所做的用户研究中更常见
it's more common in the user research that we do
只听到顾客，普通人说，
to hear just customers  regular people say
“我真的很担心人工智能对世界的影响
"I'm really worried about what the impact of AI on the world
更广泛的是。”
more broadly is going to be."
有时这意味着，你知道，
And sometimes that means  you know
工作或偏见或毒性，但有时也意味着，
jobs or bias or toxicity  but it also sometimes means like
这会扰乱世界吗？
is this just gonna mess up the world  right?
这将如何促成根本性的改变
How is this gonna contribute to fundamentally changing
人类如何协同工作、运作？
how humans work together  operate?
也就是说，我实际上没有预料到，
Which is  I wouldn't have predicted that actually
你知道？ - 哦，是的。
you know? - Oh yeah.
但是，是的，无论出于什么原因，
But yeah  for whatever reason
看起来像是 ML 研究领域的人
it seems like people in the ML research sphere
一直比较悲观
have always been more pessimistic about
AI变得非常强大——
AI becoming very powerful-
- 是的。 - 比一般公众。
- Yeah. - Than the general public.
-也许这很奇怪-
- Maybe it's a weird-
- 普通大众就像-
- General public's just like-
- 谦虚什么的，是的。
- Humility or something  yeah.
- 2023 年达里奥和我去白宫时，
- When Dario and I went to the White House in 2023
在那次会议上，比如哈里斯和雷蒙多之类的
in that meeting  like Harris and Raimondo and stuff
基本上是说，我会解释一下，
basically said  I'll paraphrase
但基本上是这样说的：“我们已经关注你们了。
but basically said like  "We've got our eye on you guys.
就像，人工智能将会变得非常重要
Like  AI's gonna be a really big deal
我们现在确实在关注，”
and we're now actually paying attention "
这是—— - 他们是对的。
which is- - And they're right.
- 他们是对的。
- They're right.
- 他们是绝对正确的。
- They're absolutely right.
完全正确。 - 但我认为2018年
Absolutely right. - But I think in 2018
你不会是这样的，
you wouldn't have been like
“总统会叫你去白宫
"The President will call you to the White House
告诉你
to tell you
他们正在密切关注
they're paying close attention to
语言模型的发展。”
the development of language models."
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 这就像一个疯狂的地方-
- Which is like a crazy place-
- 那不在宾果卡上。
- That was not on the bingo card.
- 那就像2018年。
- That was like 2018.
- 我也觉得很有趣的一件事，
- One thing that I think is interesting  too
我想，就像我们所有人都参与其中一样
just is  I guess  like all of us kind of got into this
当它看起来不存在时——
when it didn't seem like there was-
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 就像我们认为这可能发生一样，但是是的，
- Like we thought that it could happen  but yeah
就像费米对原子弹持怀疑态度一样。
it was like Fermi being skeptical of the atomic bomb.
就好像他只是一个优秀的科学家
It was like he was just a good scientist
并且有一些证据表明它可能发生，
and there was some evidence that it could happen
但也有很多证据反对这种情况的发生。
but there also was a lot of evidence against it happening.
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 我猜他认为这是值得的
- And he  I guess  decided that it would be worthwhile
因为如果这是真的，那就是一件大事了。
because if it was true  then it would be a big deal.
我想对我们所有人来说，就像，是的，
And I think for all of us  it was like  yeah
比如2015年、2016年、2017年，有一些证据
like 2015  2016  2017  there was some evidence
越来越多的证据表明这可能是一件大事，
and increasing evidence that this might be a big deal
但我记得在 2016 年，就像和我所有的顾问交谈一样——
but I remember in 2016  like talking to all my advisors-
- 是啊是啊。
- Yeah  yeah.
- 我当时想，“我已经完成了一些初创公司的工作。
- And I was like  "I've done startup stuff.
我想帮助解决人工智能安全问题
I wanna help out with AI safety
但我数学不太好。
but I'm not great at math.
我不太清楚
I don't exactly know
我怎样才能做到呢。”
how I can do it."
我想当时人们要么是这样的，
And I think at the time people either were like
“嗯，你需要非常擅长决策理论
"Well  you need to be super good at decision theory
为了提供帮助。”
in order to help out."
我当时想，“呃，这可能行不通。”
And I was like  "Eh  that's probably not gonna work."
或者他们就像，
Or they were like
“看起来确实不像
"It doesn't really seem like
我们会得到一些疯狂的人工智能东西，”
we're gonna get some crazy AI thing "
所以我基本上只有几个人
and so I had only a few people  basically
就像，
that were like
“是啊，好吧，这似乎是一件好事。”
"Yeah  okay  that seems like a good thing to do."
- 我记得是2014年
- I remember in 2014
绘制 ImageNet 结果随时间变化的图表
making graphs of ImageNet results over time
当我还是一名记者时
when I was a journalist
并试图发表有关的故事
and trying to get stories published about
人们认为我完全疯了。
and people thought I was completely mad.
然后我记得是2015年
And then I remember in 2015
试图说服布隆伯格
trying to persuade Bloomberg
让我写一个关于 NVIDIA 的故事，
to let me write a story about NVIDIA
因为每一篇人工智能研究论文都开始提到
because every AI research paper had started mentioning
GPU的使用，
the use of GPUs
他们说这完全是疯了。
and they said that was completely mad.
然后在 2016 年，当我离开新闻业进入人工智能领域时，
And then in 2016 when I left journalism to go into AI
我收到这些电子邮件说：
I have these emails saying
“你正在犯一生中最严重的错误”
"You're making the worst mistake of your life "
现在我偶尔回顾一下，
which I now occasionally look back on
但当时这一切看起来都很疯狂
but it was like it all seemed crazy at the time
从很多角度来看，
from many perspectives
认真对待这个问题，缩放会起作用，
to go and take this seriously  that scaling was gonna work
也许有什么不同
and something was maybe different about
技术范式。
the technology paradigm.
- 你就像迈克尔·乔丹和那个教练
- You're like Michael Jordan and that coach
高中时不相信他。
that didn't believe in him in high school.
- 那么你实际上是如何做出这个决定的呢？
- How did you actually make the decision  though?
你是否感到被撕裂，或者这对你来说是显而易见的？
Was it did you feel torn or was it obvious to you?
- 我做了一个疯狂的反赌，我说，
- I did a crazy counter-bet where I said
“让我成为你们的全职人工智能记者
"Let me become your full-time AI reporter
并加倍我的薪水，”
and double my salary "
我知道他们不会答应的。
which I knew that they wouldn't say yes to.
然后我就去睡觉了，然后我就醒了，然后就辞职了。
And then I went to sleep and then I woke up and resigned.
一切都相当轻松。
It was all fairly relaxed.
- 你真是个果断的人。
- You're just a decisive guy.
- 在那种情况下，我是。
- In that instance  I was.
我想是因为我想去工作
I think it's because I was like going to work
阅读档案文件，
reading archive papers
然后打印档案文件
and then printing archive papers off
回家后阅读档案文件，
and coming home and reading archive papers
包括Dario在百度的论文
including Dario's papers from the Baidu stuff
并且就像，
and being like
“这里正在发生一些完全疯狂的事情。”
"Something completely crazy is happening here."
在某些时候我认为你应该坚定地打赌，
And at some point I thought you should bet with conviction
我认为这里的每个人都在他们的职业生涯中做过这些，
which I think everyone here has done in their careers
只是坚信这会奏效。
is just betting with conviction that this is gonna work.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 我绝对没有对你那么果断。
- I definitely was not as decisive of you.
我花了大约六个月的时间
I spent  like  six months
翻转，就像，“好吧，我应该吗？
flip flopping  like  "Okay  should I  actually?
我应该这样做吗？
Should I do it?
我应该尝试创业吗？
Should I try to do a startup?
我应该尝试做这件事吗？”
Should I try to do this thing?"
- 但我也觉得那时，
- But I also feel like back then
没有太多关于工程师的讨论
there wasn't as much talk of engineers
以及工程师可以产生的影响
and the impact that an engineer can have
关于人工智能，对吗？ - 是啊，是啊，没办法。
on AI  right? - Yeah  yeah  no way.
- 现在对我们来说这感觉很自然。
- That feels so natural to us now.
我们处于同样的人才培养阶段
And we're at the same sort of talent raise
对于各种不同类型的工程师，
for engineers of all different types
但当时，就像，你是一名研究员，
but at the time  it was like  you're a researcher
这是唯一的人
and that's the only people
可以在人工智能上工作。 - 是的。
that can work on AI. - Yeah.
- 所以我不认为这很疯狂
- So I don't think it was crazy
你花时间思考这个问题。
that you were spending time thinking about that.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
是的，我认为这基本上就是问题所在
Yeah  and I think that that was basically the thing
这让我加入了 OpenAI，
that got me to join OpenAI
就像我给那里的人发信息一样，他们就像，
was like I messaged the people there and they were like
“是的，我们实际上认为你可以帮忙——”
"Yeah  we actually think that you can help out-"
- 是的。 - “通过做工程工作。”
- Yeah. - "By doing engineering work."
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- “你可以通过这种方式帮助解决人工智能安全问题。”
- "And that you can help out with AI safety in that way."
- 嗯嗯。 - 我认为
- Mm-hmm. - Which I think
确实没有这样的机会，
there hadn't really been an opportunity for that
所以这就是——
so that was what-
- 这是正确的。 - 带我去那里。
- That's right. - Brought me there.
- 你是我在 OpenAI 的经理。
- You were my manager at OpenAI.
- 我是，没错。
- I was  that's right.
- 我想我是在你在那里呆了一段时间之后才加入的。
- I think I joined after you'd been there for a while.
- 一点点。
- A little bit.
- 因为我在 Brain 呆过一段时间。
- 'Cause I was at Brain for a bit.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 我不知道我是否曾问过你
- I don't know if I ever asked you
是什么促使你加入的？
what it was that got you to join?
- 是的，所以我去过 Stripe
- Yeah  so I had been at Stripe
大约五年半
for about five and a half years
我认识格雷格；他曾经是我的老板。
and I knew Greg; he had been my boss.
他有一段时间是我在 Stripe 的老板，
He was my boss at Stripe for a while
我实际上介绍了他和达里奥，
and I actually introduced him and Dario
因为我说过，当他创办 OpenAI 时，
because I said  when he was starting OpenAI
我当时想，“我认识的最聪明的人是达里奥。
I was like  "The smartest person that I know is Dario.
如果你能得到他，你真的很幸运。”
You would be really lucky to get him."
所以 Dario 在 OpenAI，
So Dario was at OpenAI
我有几个来自 Stripe 的朋友也去过那里。
I had a few friends from Stripe that had gone there  too.
而且我觉得有点像你
And I think sort of like you
我一直在思考在 Stripe 之后我想做什么。
I'd been thinking about what I wanted to do after Stripe.
我去那里只是因为我想获得更多技能
I had gone there just 'cause I wanted to get more skills
工作之后你就知道
after working in  you know
非营利和国际发展，
nonprofit and international development
我真的以为我会回去这样做。
and I actually thought I was gonna go back to doing that.
从本质上讲，我一直在工作。
Like  essentially  I had always been working.
我当时想，“我真的很想帮助那些有的人，你知道，
I was like  "I really wanna help people that have  you know
比我少”
less than I do "
但我没有技能
but I didn't have the skills
当我在 Stripe 之前做的时候。
when I was doing it before Stripe.
- 是的。
- Yep.
- 所以我考虑回到公共卫生领域。
- And so I looked at going back to public health.
我曾短暂地考虑过重返政坛
I thought about going back into politics very briefly
但我也在寻找其他科技公司
but I was also looking around at other tech companies
以及其他产生影响的方式，
and other sort of ways of having impact
和 OpenAI 当时，
and OpenAI  at the time
感觉这是一个非常好的十字路口。
felt like it was a really nice intersection.
这是一个非营利组织，
It was a nonprofit
他们正在致力于这项非常伟大、崇高的使命。
they were working on this really big  lofty mission.
我真的相信人工智能，你知道，潜力，
I really believed in sort of the AI  you know  potential
因为，我的意思是，我对达里奥有一点了解，
because  I mean  I know Dario a little bit
所以他是——
and so he was-
- 他们需要管理帮助。
- And they needed management help.
- 绝对需要的帮助。
- The definitely needed help.
这是事实。
That is a fact.
所以我觉得这感觉很适合我，对吧？
And so I think that it felt very me-shaped  right?
我当时想，“哦，有一个非营利组织
I was like  "Oh  there's this nonprofit
还有所有这些非常伟大的人
and there's all these really great people
怀着这些真正的善意，
with these really good intentions
但看起来他们有点乱。”
but it seems like they're a little bit of a mess."
- 是的。
- Yeah.
这让我感到非常兴奋，
And that felt really exciting to me
进来，甚至，你知道，
to get to come in and even  you know
我只是一个实用型玩家，对吧？
just I was such a utility player  right?
我在跑人，
I was running people
但我也管理着一些技术团队-
but I was also running some of the technical teams-
- 扩大组织规模，是的。
- Scaling orgs  yep.
- 是的，扩展组织，
- Yeah  the scaling org
我在语言团队工作，
I worked on the language team
我接手了——
I took over-
- 你从事政策工作-
- You worked on policy-
- 我从事一些政策方面的工作，
- I worked on some policy stuff
我和克里斯一起工作，
I worked with Chris
我觉得有这么多美好
and I felt like there was just so much goodness
那里的很多员工中，
in so many of the employees there
我感到非常强烈的愿望
and I felt a very strong desire to come
有点只是尝试帮助公司发展
and sort of just try to help make the company
更实用一点。
a little more functional.
- 我记得最后，在我们完成 GPT-3 之后，
- I remember towards the end  after we'd done GPT-3
你就像，
you were like
“你们听说过一种叫做信任和安全的东西吗？”
"Have you guys heard of something called trust and safety?"
- 是的，我记得！
- Yes  I remember that!
那确实发生了。 - 是的。
That did happen. - Yeah.
- 是的。 - 我说，你知道，
- Yeah. - I said  you know
“我曾经在 Stripe 管理过一些信任和安全团队。
"I used to run some trust and safety teams at Stripe.
有一种东西叫做信任和安全
There's a thing called trust and safety
您可能会考虑采用这样的技术。”
that you might wanna consider for a technology like this."
这很有趣，因为这有点像中间步骤
And it's funny because it's sort of is the intermediary step
你知道，人工智能安全研究之间，对吧，
between  you know  AI safety research  right
这就是如何确保模型安全的真正方法
which is how do you actually make the model safe
一些更实用的东西。
to something just much more practical.
我确实认为这样说是有价值的：
I do think there was a value in saying  you know
这将是一件大事；
this is gonna be a big thing;
我们也要做这样的实际工作
we also have to be doing this sort of practical work
日复一日地锻炼肌肉
day to day to build the muscles
因为当事情变得更加危险时。
for when things are gonna be a lot higher stakes.
- 这可能是一个很好的过渡点
- That might be a good transition point
谈论诸如负责任的扩展政策之类的事情
to talk about things like the responsible scaling policy
以及我们是如何想到这一点的，
and how we came up with that
或者我们为什么想出它以及我们现在如何使用它，
or why we came up with it and how we're using it now
特别是考虑到信任和安全工作的重要性
especially given how much trust and safety work
我们在今天的模型上做到了这一点。
we do on today's models.
那么 RSP 是谁的主意呢？
So whose idea was the RSP?
是你和保罗吗？ - 所以，是的，
Was you and Paul? - So  yeah
这是我和保罗最近第一次谈论这件事，
it was me and Paul first talked about it in late
保罗·克里斯蒂安诺，2022 年末。
Paul Christiano  in late 2022.
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 首先，哦，我们是否应该将缩放上限限制在，
- First it was like  oh  should we cap scaling at a
你知道，特别一点
you know  particular point
直到我们发现如何解决某些安全问题？
until we've discovered how to solve certain safety problems?
然后就好像，嗯，你知道，
And then it was like  well  you know
有这个地方有点奇怪
it's kind of strange to have this one place
在那里你盖上盖子然后打开它，
where you cap it and then you uncap it
所以让我们有一堆阈值，
so let's have a bunch of thresholds
然后在每个阈值你必须做某些测试
and then at each threshold you have to do certain tests
看看模型是否有能力
to see if the model is capable
你必须采取
and you have to take
加强安全保障措施。
increasing safety and security measures.
但最初我们有这样的想法，
But originally we had this idea
然后我的想法就是看看，你知道，
and then the thought was just look  you know
如果由第三方来完成，效果会更好。
this'll go better if it's done by some third party.
就像，我们不应该是这样做的人，对吧？
Like  we shouldn't be the ones to do it  right?
它不应该来自一家公司，
It shouldn't come from one company
因为这样其他公司就不太可能采用它。
'cause then other companies are less likely to adopt it.
所以保罗实际上开始设计它，
So Paul actually went off and designed it
而且，你知道，它的很多很多功能都发生了变化
and  you know  many  many features of it changed
我们是站在我们这一边的，
and we were kind of  on our side
致力于研究它应该如何运作。
working on how it should work.
而且，你知道，一旦保罗在一起做某事，
And  you know  once Paul had something together
在他宣布这个概念后几乎立即，
then pretty much immediately after he announced the concept
我们在一两个月内宣布了我们的计划。
we announced ours within a month or two.
我的意思是，我们很多人都积极参与其中。
I mean  many of us were heavily involved in it.
我记得我自己至少写过一份草稿，
I remember writing at least one draft of it myself
但它有几个草稿。
but there were several drafts of it.
- 草稿太多了。
- There were so many drafts.
- 我认为它是所有文档中经过最多草稿的。
- I think it's gone through the most drafts of any doc.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 这是有道理的，对吧？
- Which makes sense  right?
就好像，我感觉就是这样
It's like  I feel like it is
就像美国对待宪法一样，
in the same way that the US treats like the Constitution
就像神圣的文件一样。
as like the holy document.
- 是的。 - 喜欢，
- Yeah. - Which like
我认为这是一件大事，可以增强美国的实力。
I think is just a big thing that like strengthens the US.
- 是的。
- Yes.
- 就像我们不认为美国会出轨一样，
- And like we don't expect the US to go off the rails
部分原因是因为就像美国的每个人一样
in part  because just like every single person in the US
就像，“宪法是一件大事，
is like  "The Constitution is a big deal
如果你踩到它——” - 是的。
and if you tread on that-" - Yeah.
- “就像，我很生气。”
- "Like  I'm mad."
- 是啊是啊。
- Yeah  yeah.
- 就像我认为 RSP 是我们的一样，
- Like I think that the RSP is our
就像，它拿着那个东西。
like  it holds that thing.
这就像人类的神圣文件。
It's like the holy document for Anthropic.
因此，值得进行大量迭代以使其正确。
So it's worth doing a lot of iterations getting it right.
- 一些我认为非常值得一看的内容
- Some of what I think has been so cool to watch
关于 Anthropic 的 RSP 开发，
about the RSP development at Anthropic  too
是不是感觉已经经历了
is it feels like it has gone through
这么多不同的阶段
so many different phases
还有很多不同的技能
and there's so many different skills
让它发挥作用所需要的，对吗？
that are needed to make it work  right?
有一些伟大的想法，
There's like the big ideas
我觉得就像达里奥、保罗、山姆和贾里德
which I feel like Dario and Paul and Sam and Jared
还有很多人会问，“原则是什么？
and so many others are like  "What are the principles?
就像我们想说什么？
Like what are we trying to say?
我们怎么知道我们的想法是否正确？”
How do we know if we're right?"
但也有这种非常具有操作性的方法
But there's also this very operational approach
只是迭代
to just iterating
我们就像，“好吧，我们认为
where we're like  "Well  we thought that
我们将会看到这个，你知道，安全级别，
we were gonna see this at this  you know  safety level
而我们没有，
and we didn't
那么我们应该改变它以确保
so should we change it so that we're making sure that
我们要对自己负责吗？”
we're holding ourselves accountable?"
然后还有各种组织方面的事情，对吗？
And then there's all kinds of organizational things  right?
我们只是想，
We just were like
“让我们改变 RSP 组织的结构
"Let's change the structure of the RSP organization
以获得更明确的责任。”
for clearer accountability."
我认为我的感觉是对于一份文件
And I think my sense is that for a document
这和这个一样重要，对吧，
that's as important as this  right
我喜欢宪法的比喻，
I love the Constitution analogy
就好像有所有这些机构和系统
it's like there's all of these bodies and systems
存在于美国
that exist in the US
确保我们遵守宪法，对吧？
to make sure that we follow the Constitution  right?
有法院，有最高法院，
There's the courts  there's the Supreme Court
有总统职位，
there's the presidency
你知道，国会两院都有
there's  you know  both houses of Congress
当然，他们还做各种各样的其他事情，
and they do all kinds of other things  of course
但你需要的所有这些基础设施都有
but there's like all of this infrastructure that you need
围绕这个文件，
around this one document
我觉得我们也在这里吸取了教训。
and I feel like we're also learning that lesson here.
- 我认为这反映了一种观点
- I think it sort of reflects a view
我们很多人都关心安全，
a lot of us have about safety
这是一个可以解决的问题。
which is that it's a solvable problem.
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 这只是一个非常非常困难的问题
- It's just a very  very hard problem
这需要大量的工作。
that's gonna take tons and tons of work.
- 嗯嗯。 - 是的。
- Mm-hmm. - Yeah.
- 我们需要建立的所有这些机构，
- All of these institutions that we need to build up
就像周围建立了各种各样的机构
like there's all sorts of institutions built up around
就像汽车安全一样，经过很多很多年的积累。
like automotive safety  built up over many  many years.
但我们会想，“我们有时间这样做吗？
But we're like  "Do we have the time to do that?
我们必须尽快找出答案
We've gotta go as fast as we can to figure out
我们需要什么样的人工智能安全机构，
what the institutions we need for AI safety are
并尝试首先在这里构建它们，
and build those and try to build them here first
但要使其可出口。”
but make it exportable."
- 这是正确的。
- That's right.
- 它也迫使团结，
- It it forces unity also
因为如果组织的任何部分
because if any part of the org
有点不符合我们的安全价值观，
is not kind of in line with our safety values
它通过 RSP 的形式出现，对吧？
it shows up through kind of the RSP  right?
RSP 会阻止他们做他们想做的事
The RSP is gonna block them from doing what they want to do
所以这是一个不断提醒大家的方式，
and so it's a way to remind everyone over and over again
基本上，为了使安全成为产品要求，
basically  to make safety a product requirement
产品规划过程的一部分。
part of the product planning process.
所以，就像，这不仅仅是一堆类似的东西
And so  like  it's not just a bunch of kind of like
我们重复的溴化物；
bromides that we repeat;
这实际上是你的事情
it's something that you actually
如果你出现在这里并且你没有对齐，
if you show up here and you're not aligned
你实际上遇到了它。
you actually run into it.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 你要么必须学会适应这个程序
- And you either have to learn to get with the program
或者它不起作用。 - 是的。
or it doesn't work out. - Yeah.
- 随着时间的推移，RSP 变得有点有趣
- The RSPs become kind of funny over time
因为我们在上面花费了数千个小时的工作，
because we spend thousands of hours of work on it
然后我去和参议员交谈并解释 RSP，
and then I go and talk to senators and I explain the RSP
我说，“我们有一些东西
and I'm like  "We have some stuff
这意味着我们制造的东西很难被盗，
that means it's hard to steal what we make
而且它是安全的。”
and also that it's safe."
他们就像，
And they're like
“是的，这是一件完全正常的事情。
"Yes  that's a completely normal thing to do.
你是告诉我不是每个人都这样做吗？”
Are you telling me not everyone does this?"
你会说，“哦，好吧，是的。”
You're like  "Oh  okay  yeah."
是的。
Yeah.
- 并非每个人都这样做，这对一半是真的。
- It's half true that that not everyone does this.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 但是那种，
- But that kind of
这太神奇了，因为我们在这里花了很多精力
it's amazing because we've spent so much effort on it here
当你把它煮沸时，他们就像，
and when you boil it down  they're like
“是的，这听起来像是正常的方式
"Yes  that sounds like a normal way
这样做。” - 是的，听起来不错。
to do that." - Yeah  that sounds good.
- 这就是目标。
- That's been the goal.
正如丹妮拉所说，
Like Daniela was saying
“让我们让这变得无聊和正常。
"Let's make this as boring and normal.
就像让我们把这变成一个金融问题。”
Like let's make this a finance thing."
- 是的，想象一下这就像一次审计。
- Yeah  imagine it's like an audit.
- 是啊是啊。 - 正确的？
- Yeah  yeah. - Right?
是的。 - 不，无聊又正常
Yeah. - No  boring and normal
就是我们想要的，
is what we want
当然现在回想起来。 - 是的。
certainly in retrospect. - Yeah.
还有，达里奥，
Well also  Dario
我认为除了驱动对齐之外，
I think in addition to driving alignment
它还可以提高清晰度- - 嗯嗯。
it also drives clarity- - Mm-hmm.
- 因为它写下了我们想要做的事情
- Because it's written down what we're trying to do
公司里的每个人都可以清楚地看到，
and it's legible to everyone in the company
并且从外部清晰可见
and it's legible externally
我们认为我们应该实现的目标
what we think we're supposed to be aiming towards
从安全角度来看。
from a safety perspective.
它并不完美。
It's not perfect.
我们正在迭代它，我们正在使它变得更好，
We're iterating on it  we're making it better
但我认为这样说是有一定价值的
but I think there's some value in saying like
“这就是我们担心的，这里的东西。”
"This is what we're worried about  this thing over here."
就像你不能只用这个词来排序
Like you can't just use this word to sort of
朝任一方向脱轨，对吗？
derail something in either direction  right?
说，“哦，出于安全考虑，我们不能做 X，
To say  "Oh  because of safety  we can't do X
或者出于安全考虑，我们必须做X。”
or because of safety  we have to do X."
我们确实在努力让我们的意思更清楚。
We're really trying to make it clearer what we mean.
- 是的，它可以让你不用担心
- Yeah  it prevents you from worrying about
阳光下的每一件小事。
every last little thing under the sun.
- 这是正确的。
- That's right.
- 因为这实际上是消防演习
- Because it's actually the fire drills
从长远来看，这会损害安全。
that damage the cause of safety in the long run.
- 正确的。
- Right.
- 我说过，“如果有一座建筑物，
- I've said like  "If there's a building
而且，你知道，火警警报每周都会响起，
and  you know  the fire alarm goes off every week
就像，那是一座非常不安全的建筑。”
like  that's a really unsafe building."
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 因为当真的发生火灾时
- 'Cause when there's like actually a fire
你只会像- - 没人会在乎。
you're just gonna be like- - No ones gonna care.
- “哦，它总是响。”
- "Oh  it just goes off all the time."
所以- - 是的。
So- - Yeah.
- 校准非常重要。
- It's very important to be calibrated.
- 是的。 - 这是正确的。
- Yeah. - That's right.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
一个稍微不同的框架，我觉得有点澄清
A slightly different frame that I find kind of clarifying
我认为 RSP 创造了健康的激励
is that I think that RSP creates healthy incentives
在很多层面上。 - 毫米。
at a lot of levels. - Mm.
- 所以我认为它在内部是一致的
- So I think internally it aligns
安全激励每个团队
the incentives of every team with safety
因为这意味着如果我们不在安全方面取得进展
because it means that if we don't make progress on safety
我们要阻止。
we're gonna block.
我也认为在外部
I also think that externally
它创造了很多更健康的激励
it creates a lot of healthier incentives
与其他可能性相比，至少我认为，
than other possibilities  at least that I see
因为这意味着，你知道，如果我们在某个时刻
because it means that  you know  if we at some point
必须采取某种戏剧性的行动，
have to take some kind of dramatic action
就像，如果在某个时候我们不得不说，
like  if at some point we have to say
“你知道，我们的模型，我们已经达到了某个点
"You know  our model  we've reached some point
我们还无法确保模型安全，”
and we can't yet make a model safe "
它与某种点对齐
it aligns that with sort of the point where
有证据支持该决定
there's evidence that supports that decision
并且有一个预先存在的框架
and there's sort of a preexisting framework
想想看，它是清晰的。
for thinking about it  and it's legible.
所以我认为 RSP 有很多级别，
And so I think there's a lot of levels at which the RSP
我以我最初可能不理解的方式思考
I think in ways that maybe I didn't initially understand
当我们谈论它的早期版本时
when we were talking about the early versions of it
它创建了一个更好的框架
it creates a better framework
比我考虑过的其他任何一个都重要。
than any of the other ones that I've thought about.
- 我认为这都是真的
- I think this is all true
但我觉得它的售价有点像
but I feel like it undersells sort of like
弄清楚是多么具有挑战性
how challenging it's been to sort of figure out
什么是正确的政策和评估
what the right policies and evaluations
以及线条应该是什么。
and what the lines should be.
我认为我们已经并将继续
I think that we have and continue to
对此进行了很多迭代，
sort of iterate a lot on that
我认为还有一个问题也很难
and I think there is a question also that's difficult
你可能正处于某个时刻
of sort of you could be at a point where
很明显有东西很危险
it's very clear something's dangerous
或者非常清楚某些东西是安全的，
or very clear that something's safe
但有了一些如此新颖的技术
but with some technology that's so new
实际上有一个很大的灰色区域。
there's actually like a big gray area.
所以我认为这就像，
And so I think that has been  like
我们所说的所有事情
all the things that we're saying
是那些让我
were things that made me
一开始对 RSP 真的非常非常兴奋，
really  really excited about the RSP at the beginning
并且仍然这样做，
and still do
但我也认为制定这个
but also I think enacting this
以清晰的方式并使其发挥作用
in a clear way and making it work
变得更加困难和复杂
has been much harder and more complicated
超出我的预期。
than I anticipated.
- 是的，我认为这正是重点。
- Yeah  I think this is exactly the point.
就像- - 是的。
Like- - Yeah.
- 就像灰色地带是无法预测的一样。
- Like the gray areas are impossible to predict.
他们有很多。
There's so many of them.
就像，直到你真正尝试实现一切，
Like  until you actually try to implement everything
你不知道会出什么问题。
you don't know what's going to go wrong.
所以我们要做的就是去实施一切
So what we're trying to do is go and implement everything
这样我们就能尽早发现会出现什么问题
so we can see as early as possible what's going to go wrong
所以- -是的，你必须-
so- - Yeah  you have to-
- 灰色区域是-
- The gray areas are-
- 你必须先经过三四遍-
- You have to do three or four passes before-
- 是的。 - 是的。
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 在你真正真正做好之前。
- Before you really  really get it right.
就像，迭代非常强大，你知道，
Like  iteration is just very powerful and  you know
你不可能第一次就做对。
you're not gonna get it right on the first time.
所以，你知道，如果赌注增加，
And so  you know  if the stakes are increasing
您希望尽早进行迭代；
you want to get your iterations in early;
你不想让他们迟到。
you don't want to get them in late.
- 你也在建造
- You're also building
内部机构和流程，
the internal institutions and processes
所以细节可能会发生很大变化，
so the specifics might change a lot
但只要这样做就可以锻炼肌肉
but building the muscle of just doing it
才是真正有价值的东西。
is the really valuable thing.
- 我负责 Anthropic 的计算，等等 -
- I'm responsible for  like  compute at Anthropic  and so-
- 这很重要。
- That's important.
- 那么，谢谢你。
- So  thank you.
我想是的。
I think so.
所以就像对我来说，
So like for me
就像我想我们必须与外部人员打交道-
like I guess we have to deal with external folks-
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 以及不同的外部人员
- And different external folks
属于不同的范围，比如，
kind of are on different spectrums of the  like
他们认为事情会变得多快？
how fast do they think stuff is gonna get?
- 嗯嗯。 - 就像，
- Mm-hmm. - And like
我想这也是一个事情
I think that's also been a thing
我一开始就喜欢不思考任何事情
where I started out like not thinking stuff
会那么快并且随着时间的推移而改变。
would be that fast and have changed over time.
因此，我对此表示同情。
And so  I have sympathy for that.
所以我认为 RSP 对我来说非常有用
And so I think the RSP has been extremely useful for me
在与人交往中
in communicating with people
谁认为事情可能需要更长的时间
who think that things might take longer
因为我们有这样的事情，
because then we have a thing where it's like
我们不需要采取极端的安全措施
we don't need to do extreme safety measures
直到事情变得非常激烈，
until stuff gets really intense
然后他们可能会这样，
and then they might be like
“我不认为事情会在很长一段时间内变得激烈。”
"I don't think stuff will get intense for a long time."
然后我就会像，
And then I'll be like
“好吧，是的，我们不必采取极端的安全措施。”
"Okay  yeah  we don't have to do extreme safety measures."
这样就容易多了
And so that makes it a lot easier
与外界的其他人交流。
to communicate with other folks externally.
- 是的，是的，它就像
- Yeah  yeah  it makes it like
一件很平常的事情，你可以谈论，
a normal thing you can talk about
而不是真正奇怪的事情。
rather than something really strange.
- 是的。 - 是的。
- Yeah. - Yeah.
它还能以什么方式呈现给人们呢？
How else is it showing up for people?
你是-
You are-
- 评估，评估，评估。
- Evals  evals  evals.
- 好的。
- Good.
- 这都是关于评估的。
- It's all about evals.
大家都在做评估。
Everyone's doing evals.
就像，您的培训团队一直在进行评估。
Like  your training team is doing evals all the time.
我们试图弄清楚，比如，
We're trying to figure out  like
这个模型已经足够好了吗
has this model gotten enough better
它有潜在危险吗？
that it has the potential to be dangerous?
那么我们有多少个团队是评估团队？
So how many teams do we have that are evals teams?
你有边境红队。
You have Frontier Red Team.
一定有，我是说有很多人-
There must be  I mean there's a lot of people-
- 基本上每个团队都会进行评估。
- Every team produces evals  basically.
- 这意味着你只是根据 RSP 进行衡量，
- And that means you're just measuring against the RSP
就像测量某些迹象
like measuring for certain signs of
您关心或不关心的事情。
things that would concern you or not concern you.
- 确切地。
- Exactly.
就像很容易降低模型的能力一样，
Like it's easy to lower bound the abilities of a model
但很难达到上限，
but it's hard to upper bound
所以我们投入了大量的研究工作
so we just put tons and tons of research effort
说，比如，
into saying  like
“这个模型能不能做这种危险的事情？
"Can this model do this dangerous thing or not?
或许还有一些我们没有想到的技巧，
Maybe there's some trick that we haven't thought of
像思想链或最好的事件
like chain of thought or best event
或者某种工具的使用可以做到这一点
or some kind of tool use that's gonna make it
所以它可以帮助你做一些非常危险的事情。”
so it can help you do something very dangerous."
- 这在政策上确实很有用，
- It's been really useful in policy
因为这是一个非常抽象的概念
because it's been a really abstract concept
什么是安全，
what safety is
当我说“我们有一个评估
and when I'm like  "We have an eval
无论我们是否部署模型，这都会改变，”
which changes whether we deploy the model or not "
然后你可以去校准
and then you can go and calibrate with
国家安全政策制定者或专家
policymakers or experts in national security
或我们所做的一些 CBRN 领域，
or some of these CBRN areas that we do
真正帮助我们构建经过良好校准的评估
to actually help us build evals that are well-calibrated
与事实相反，
and that  counter-factually
否则就不会发生
just wouldn't have happened otherwise
但一旦你知道了具体的事情
but once you've got the specific thing
人们更有动力
people are a lot more motivated
帮助您使其准确，
to help you make it accurate
所以它对此很有用。
so it's been useful for that.
它如何显示- - RSP 对我显示，
How has it shown up for- - The RSP shows up for me
一定。
for sure.
经常。
Often.
其实我觉得很奇怪
I actually think  weirdly
我对 RSP 最感兴趣的方式是
the way that I think about the RSP the most is like
听起来像什么——
what it sounds like-
- 嗯嗯？
- Mm-hmm?
- 就像语气一样。
- Just like the tone.
我认为我们刚刚对 RSP 的语气进行了重大重写
I think we just did a big rewrite of the tone of the RSP
因为感觉过于技术官僚，
because it felt overly technocratic
甚至有点敌对。
and even a little bit adversarial.
我花了很多时间思考，
I spent a lot of time thinking about like
你如何构建一个系统
how do you build a system
人们只是想成为其中的一部分？
that people just wanna be a part of?
- 嗯嗯。 - 正确的？
- Mm-hmm. - Right?
如果有 RSP 就更好了
It's so much better if the RSP is something
公司里的每个人都可以四处走动并告诉你，
that everyone in the company can walk around and tell you
你知道，就像 OKR 一样
you know  just like with OKRs
就像我们现在做的那样--是的。
like we do right now- - Yeah.
- 比如，RSP 的最高目标是什么？
- Like  what are the top goals of the RSP?
我们怎么知道我们是否会见他们？
How do we know if we're meeting them?
我们现在的人工智能安全水平是多少？
What AI safety level are we at right now?
我们处于 ASL-2 水平吗？
Are we at ASL-2?
我们处于 ASL-3 水平吗？
Are we at ASL-3?
人们知道要寻找什么
That people know what to look for
因为这就是你将会拥有的
because that is how you're going to have
如果出现问题，良好的常识，
good  common knowledge of if something's going wrong
正确的？
right?
如果过于技术化的话
If it's overly technocratic
这就是
and it's something that
仅公司中的特定人员
only particular people in the company
他们可以感受到，
feel is accessible to them
就好像效率不高一样，对吧？
it's just like not as productive  right?
我认为这真的很酷
And I think it's been really cool
观看它如何过渡到本文档中
to watch it sort of transition into this document
其实我最想的地方
where I actually think most
如果不是公司里的每个人，无论他们的角色如何，
if not everybody at the company  regardless of their role
读完之后会说：“这感觉真的很合理。
could read it and say  "This feels really reasonable.
我想确保我们正在构建人工智能
I wanna make sure that we're building AI
通过以下方式，
in the following ways
我明白为什么我会担心这些事情
and I see why I would be worried about these things
我也知道要寻找什么
and I also kind of know what to look for
如果我撞到什么东西，”对吧？
if I bump into something " right?
这几乎就像让它变得足够简单
It's almost like make it simple enough
如果你在一家制造工厂工作
that if you are working at a manufacturing plant
你就像，
and you're like
“呃，这个好像是安全带
"Huh  it looks like the safety seatbelt on this
应该以这种方式连接，但它没有连接，”
should connect this way  but it doesn't connect "
你可以发现它。
that you can spot it.
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 而且就像健康的反馈流一样
- And that there's just like healthy feedback flow
领导层和董事会之间
between leadership and the board
以及公司的其他成员
and the rest of the company
以及实际构建它的人们，
and the people that are actually building it
因为我实际上认为这件事出了问题
because I actually think the way this stuff goes wrong
在大多数情况下，就像电线没有连接一样
in most cases is just  like  the wires don't connect
或者就像他们被交叉一样，
or like they get crossed
那就像
and that would just be like
事情出错真是令人悲伤，对吧？
a really sad way for things to go wrong  right?
这只是关于操作它，
It's just all about operationalizing it
使人们易于理解。
making it easy for people to understand.
- 是的，我想说的是
- Yeah  the thing I would say is
我们谁都不想成立一家公司。
none of us wanted to found a company.
我们只是觉得这是我们的责任，对吗？
We just felt like it was our duty  right?
- 感觉我们必须这样做。
- It felt like we had to.
- 就像，我们必须做这件事。
- Like  we have to do this thing.
这就是我们利用人工智能让事情变得更好的方式。
This is the way we're gonna make things go better with AI.
这也是我们做出承诺的原因，对吧？
Like that's also why we did the pledge  right?
- 是的。 - 因为我们就像
- Yeah. - Because we're like
我们这样做的原因是感觉这是我们的责任。
the reason we're doing this is it feels like our duty.
- 我想发明和发现事物
- I wanted to invent and discover things
以某种有益的方式。
in some kind of beneficial way.
这就是我的想法，这导致了我对人工智能的研究，
That was how I came to it  and that led to working on AI
人工智能需要大量的工程技术
and AI required a lot of engineering
最终人工智能需要大量资金，
and eventually AI required a lot of capital
但我发现的是
but what I found was that
如果你不这样做
if you don't do this in a way where
你在设置环境，
you're setting the environment
您在哪里设立公司，
where you set up the company
然后很多事情就完成了
then a lot of it gets done
很多人都在重复同样的错误
a lot of it repeats the same mistakes
我发现科技界是如此疏远。
that I found so alienating about the tech community.
都是同一群人，
It's the same people
都是一样的态度
it's the same attitude
这是相同的模式匹配，
it's the same pattern-matching
所以在某些时候这似乎是不可避免的
And so at some point it just seemed inevitable
我们需要以不同的方式来做这件事。
that we need to do it in a different way.
- 当我们在研究生院闲逛时
- When we were hanging out in graduate school
我记得你有这样的整个计划
I remember you had kind of this whole program
试图弄清楚如何做科学
of trying to figure out how to do science
以某种方式促进公共利益。
in a way that would sort of advance the public good.
我认为这非常类似于
And I think that's pretty similar to
我们如何看待这个问题。
how we we think about this.
我想你有类似 Vannevar 计划之类的东西，
I think you had this like Project Vannevar or something
这样做。
to do that.
我是一名教授。
I was a professor.
我想基本上我只是看看情况
I think basically I just looked at the situation
我确信人工智能
and I was convinced that AI
处于非常非常陡峭的轨道上
was on a very  very  very steep trajectory
就影响力而言，
in terms of impact
看起来并不是因为需要资本，
didn't seem like because of the necessity for capital
作为一名物理学教授，我可以继续这样做
and as a physics professor  I could continue doing that
我有点想和我信任的人一起工作
and I kind of wanted to work with people that I trusted
建立一个机构来努力让人工智能顺利发展。
in building an institution to try to make AI go well.
但是，是的，我永远不会建议成立一家公司。
But yeah  I would never recommend founding a company.
或者说真的很想做。
Or really want to do it.
我的意思是，是的，我认为这只是达到目的的一种手段。
I mean  yeah  I think it's just a means to an end.
我是说，
I mean
不过，我认为事情通常都会顺利进行。
I think that's like usually how things go well  though.
如果你做某事只是为了有点像
If you're doing something just to sort of like
充实自己或获得权力，或者，
enrich yourself or gain power or  like
你必须真正关心
you have to sort of actually care about
实现世界上真正的目标
accomplishing a real goal in the world
然后你就会找到你所需要的一切手段。
and then you find whatever means you have to.
- 嗯，我经常思考的事情
- Well  something I think about a lot
正如我们的战略优势一样，
as just a strategic advantage for us is
我的意思是，听起来真的很有趣，
I mean  it sounds really funny to say
但就像这张桌子上有多少信任一样，
but just like how much trust there is at this table
正确的？ - 嗯嗯。
right? - Mm-hmm.
- 就像我认为那不是，我的意思是，
- Like I think that's not  I mean
汤姆，你曾在其他初创公司工作过。
Tom  you were at other startups.
我以前从来没有当过创始人
I was never a founder before
但其实要组团真的很难
but it's actually really hard to get a group of
就像一大群人，有同样的使命。
like  a big group of people  to have like the same mission.
正确的？
Right?
我认为我感到最幸福的事情
And I think the thing that I feel like the happiest about
当我上班的时候
when I come into work
也许是 Anthropic 最值得骄傲的，
and probably the most proud of at Anthropic
是它对很多人的影响有多好。
is how well that has scaled to a lot of people.
我感觉就像在这个团体中
It feels to me like in this group
以及其他领导层，
and with the rest of leadership
大家都是为了使命而来
everyone is here for the mission
我们的使命非常明确——
and our mission is really clear-
- 是的。 - 而且很纯粹，对吧？
- Yep. - And it's very pure  right?
我认为这是我不常看到的事情
And I think that is something that I don't see as often
按照达里奥的观点，在科技行业中。
to Dario's point  in sort of the tech industry.
感觉就像有一种健康的感觉
It feels like there's just a wholesomeness
我们正在努力做的事情。
to what we're trying to do.
就像，不，我同意，我们没有人喜欢，
Like  no  I agree  none of us were like
“我们去找个公司吧！”
"Let's just go found a company!"
我觉得我们必须这样做，对吧？
I felt like we had to do it  right?
感觉就像
It just felt like
我们无法继续做我们正在做的事情
we couldn't keep doing what we were doing
在我们做这件事的地方。
at the place we were doing it.
我们必须自己做。
We had to do it by ourselves.
- 感觉就像 GPT-3，
- And it felt like with GPT-3
你知道，我们所有人都曾接触过或做过这件事，
you know  which all of us had like touched or worked on
以及缩放定律和其他一切，
and scaling laws and everything else
2020 年我们就能看到它。
we could see it in front of us in 2020.
感觉就像，嗯，
And it felt like  well
如果我们不尽快一起做点什么
if we don't do something soon  all together
你将会到达无法回头的地步。
you're gonna hit the point of no return.
你必须做点什么
And you have to do something
拥有改变环境的能力。
to have any ability to change the environment.
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 我认为，以丹妮拉为基础，
- I think  building off Daniela
我确实认为有很多信任-
I do think that there's just like a lot of trust-
- 嗯嗯。 - 在这个组中。
- Mm-hmm. - In this group.
我想我们每个人都知道我们陷入了这个困境
I think each of us knows that we got into this
因为我们想为世界提供帮助。
because we wanna help out with the world.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 我们做到了 80% 的承诺，
- We did the the 80% pledge thing
这就像每个人都喜欢的事情，
and that was like a thing that everybody was just like
“是的，显然我们会这么做。”
"Yes  obviously we're gonna do this."
- 嗯嗯。 - 是啊是啊。
- Mm-hmm. - Yeah  yeah.
- 是的，我确实认为信任是一件事
- And yeah  I do think that the trust thing
是一种极为罕见的特殊事物。
is a special thing that's extremely rare.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 我相信丹妮拉保持了高标准。
- I credit Daniela with keeping the bar high.
我相信你的事实——
I credit you with the fact-
- 把小丑拒之门外。
- Keeping out the clowns.
把小丑拒之门外。
Keeping out the clowns.
- 首席小丑争吵者！
- Chief clown wrangler!
这就是我的工作。
That's my job.
- 不，但我认为你是文化规模扩大的原因。
- No  but you're the reason the culture scaled  I think.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
人们说这里的人多么好。
People say how nice people are here.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 这实际上是一件非常重要的事情。
- Which is actually a wildly important thing.
- 我认为人择是非常低级的政治，
- I think Anthropic is really low politics
当然，
and of course
我们都有比一般人不同的优势，
we all have a different vantage point than average
我试着记住这一点。 - 这是因为自我意识低下。
and I try to remember that. - It's because of low ego.
- 但它的自我意识很低，
- But it's low ego
我想我确实认为我们的面试过程
and I think I do think our interview process
以及在这里工作的人类型，
and just the type of people who work here
就像，人们对政治几乎有类似的过敏反应。
like  there's almost a like allergic reaction to politics.
- 和团结。
- And unity.
- 嗯嗯。 - 团结是如此重要。
- Mm-hmm. - Unity is so important.
产品团队、研究团队的想法——
The idea that the product team  the research team-
- 是的。
- Yes.
- 信任和安全团队，
- The trust and safety team
你知道，进入市场团队、政策团队——
you know  the go-to market team  the policy team-
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 就像安全人员一样，
- Like  the safety folks
他们都在努力为同一个目标做出贡献，
they're all trying to contribute to kind of the same goal
企业同样的使命，
the same mission of the company
正确的？ - 是的。
right? - Yes.
- 我认为这是功能失调的时候
- I think it's dysfunctional when
公司的不同部门
different parts of the company
认为他们正在尝试完成不同的事情-
think they're trying to accomplish different things-
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 考虑公司不同的事情
- Think the company's about different things
或者认为公司的其他部门
or think that other parts of the company
正在试图破坏他们正在做的事情。
are trying to undermine what they're doing.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 我认为最重要的是
- And I think the most important thing
我们设法保存的是，
we've managed to preserve is
再说一次，像 RSP 这样的东西推动它，
and again  things like the RSP drive it
这个想法不是，你知道，
this idea that it's not  you know
公司的某些部门造成了损害
there's some parts of the company causing damage
以及公司的其他部门试图修复它，
and other parts of the company trying to repair it
但公司有不同的部门
but that there are different parts of the company
执行不同的功能
doing different functions
并且它们都在单一的变革理论下发挥作用。
and that they all function under a single theory of change.
- 极端实用主义，对吗？
- Extreme pragmatism  right?
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 你知道，我当初选择 OpenAI 的原因是
- You know  the reason I went to OpenAI in the first place
你知道，这是一个非营利组织
you know  it was a nonprofit
这是一个我可以去关注安全的地方，
it was a place where I could go and focus on safety
我想随着时间的推移，你知道，
and I think over time  you know
这可能不太合适
that maybe wasn't as good a fit
并且做出了一些艰难的决定。
and there were some difficult decisions.
我认为，在很多方面，
And I think  in a lot of ways
在这一点上我真的很信任达里奥和丹妮拉，
I really trusted Dario and Daniela on that
但我不想离开。
but I didn't want to leave.
那是我认为我实际上是的东西
That was something that I think I was actually
很不愿意一起去，
pretty reluctant to go along with
因为我认为，一方面，
because I think  for one thing
我不知道这对世界有好处
I didn't know that it was good for the world
拥有更多的人工智能实验室。
to have more AI labs.
我认为这就是
And I think it was something that
我当时很漂亮，很不情愿。
I was pretty  pretty reluctant for.
我也想，当我们离开时，
And I think  as well  when we did leave
我想我当时不愿意创办一家公司。
I think I was  you know  I was reluctant to start a company.
我想我已经争论了很长时间了
I think I was arguing for a long time
我们应该做一个非营利组织
that we should do a nonprofit instead
并专注于安全研究。
and just focus on safety research.
- 是的。
- Yes.
- 我认为这确实需要实用主义
- And I think it really took pragmatism
并面对限制
and confronting the constraints
并诚实地了解这些限制意味着什么
and just being honest about what the constraints implied
为了完成这个使命——
for accomplishing that mission-
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 这导致了人择。
- That led to Anthropic.
- 我认为这是一个非常重要的教训
- I think just a really important lesson
我们一开始就很擅长
that we were good about early on
就是少做承诺，多兑现承诺。
is make less promises and keep more of them.
- 是的。 - 正确的？
- Yeah. - Right?
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 就像，尝试校准，现实一点，
- Like  try to be calibrated  be realistic
面对权衡，因为，你知道，
confront the trade-offs  because  you know
信任和信誉
trust and credibility
比任何特定政策都更重要。
are more important than any particular policy.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 拥有我们所拥有的东西真是太不寻常了，
- It is so unusual to have what we have
并观看迈克·克里格 (Mike Krieger) 捍卫安全事务，
and watching Mike Krieger defend safety things
我们不应该发货产品的类似原因，
of like reasons why we shouldn't ship a product yet
然后还看到 Vinay 说，
but also then to watch Vinay sort of say like
“好吧，我们必须为企业做正确的事情。
"Okay  we have to do the right thing for the business.
比如我们如何才能冲过终点线？”
Like how do we get this across the finish line?"
- 嗯嗯，是的。
- Mm-hmm  yep.
- 听到，你知道，
- And to hear  you know
人们喜欢深入技术安全组织
people like deep in the technical safety org
谈论我们构建事物的重要性
talking about how it's also important that we build things
对人们实用的，
that are practical for people
听到，你知道，
and hearing  you know
工程师们在推理中谈论安全性。
engineers on inference talk about safety.
太棒了。
That's amazing.
就像，我想，再一次，
Like  I think that is  again
在这里工作最特别的事情之一
one of the most special things about working here
是不是每个人都团结一致，优先考虑实用主义，
is everybody with that unity is prioritizing the pragmatism
安全、业务。
the safety  the business.
那太疯狂了。
That's wild.
- 最安全的举动- - 我认为这是-
- The safest move- - I think about it as-
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 分散权衡- - 是的。
- Spreading the trade-offs- - Yeah.
- 从公司领导到每个人，
- From just the leadership of the company to everyone
正确的？ - 是的。
right? - Yeah.
- 我认为功能失调的世界就像，
- I think the dysfunctional world is like
你知道，有一群人只看到大事
you have a bunch of people who only see a big  you know
安全就像“我们总是必须这样做”
safety is like  "We always have to do this "
产品就像是“我们总是必须这样做”
and product is like  "We always have to do this "
研究就像，你知道，
and research is like  you know
“这是我们唯一关心的事情。”
"This is the only thing we care about."
然后你就被困在顶端了
And then you're stuck at the top
正确的？ - 是的。
right? - Yeah.
- 你被困在顶部了。
- You're stuck at the top.
你必须在两者之间做出决定
You have to decide between
你没有他们中的任何一个拥有那么多的信息。
you don't have as much information as either of them.
这就是功能失调的世界。
That's the dysfunctional world.
函数世界是当
The functional world is when
你能够与每个人沟通，
you're able to communicate to everyone
“我们都面临着这些权衡。”
"There are these trade-offs we're all facing together."
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 世界远非完美。
- The world is a far from perfect place.
只是需要权衡。
There's just trade-offs.
你所做的一切都将是次优的。
Everything you do is gonna be suboptimal.
你所做的一切都将是
Everything you do is gonna be
一些人试图两全其美，你知道，
some attempt to get the best of both worlds that  you know
并没有你想象的那么好
doesn't work out as well as you thought it was
每个人都在同一页上
and everyone is on the same page about
共同面对这些权衡，
confronting those trade-offs together
他们只是觉得自己正在面对他们
and they just feel like they're confronting them
来自特定帖子。
from a particular post.
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 来自特定工作，作为整体工作的一部分
- From a particular job  as part of the overall job of
面对所有的权衡。
confronting all the trade-offs.
- 这是一场争夺巅峰的赌注，对吗？
- It's a bet on race to the top  right?
- 这是对力争上游的赌注，是的。
- It's a bet on race to the top  yeah.
- 好像这不是一个纯粹的上行赌注。
- Like it's not a pure upside bet.
事情可能会出错，但是——
Things could go wrong  but-
- 是的。 - 喜欢，
- Yeah. - Like
我们都一致同意，
we're all aligned on like
“这就是我们所打的赌注。”
"This is the bet that we're making."
- 市场是务实的，
- And markets are pragmatic
所以如果 Anthropic 作为一家公司变得更加成功，
so if the more successful Anthropic becomes as a company
人们越有动力去复制
the more incentive there is for people to copy
让我们成功的事情。
the things that make us successful.
成功与否的联系越紧密
And the more that success is tied to
我们所做的实际安全工作，
actual safety stuff we do
它创造的越多
the more it just creates
行业引力
a gravitational force in the industry
这实际上会让其他行业参与竞争。
that will actually get the rest of industry to compete.
就像，“当然，我们会制造安全带
And it's like  "Sure  we'll build seat belts
其他人都可以复制它们。”
and everyone else can copy them."
那挺好的。
That's good.
是的。
Yeah.
- 这就像美好的世界。
- That's like good world.
- 那真是太好了。 - 是的。
- That's really good. - Yeah.
这就是登顶的竞赛，对吗？
This is the race to the top  right?
但如果你说，
But if you're saying
“好吧，我们不会开发这项技术，
"Well  we're not gonna build the technology
你不会比其他人建造得更好，”
you're not gonna build it better than someone else "
到最后，
that in the end
那是行不通的，因为你没有证明
that just doesn't work because you're not proving
从这里到那里是可能的。
that it's possible to get from here to there.
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 世界需要到达的地方，
- Where the world needs to get
不在乎这个行业，不在乎一家公司，
nevermind the industry  nevermind one company
是否需要让我们成功度过
is it needs to get us successfully through from
这项技术不存在
this technology does-doesn't exist
该技术以非常强大的方式存在
to the technology exists in a very powerful way
社会实际上已经做到了这一点。
and society has actually managed it.
我认为唯一能实现这一点的方法
And I think the only way that's gonna happen
是如果你在一家公司的层面上
is that if you have  at the level of a single company
最终在行业层面，
and eventually at the level of the industry
你实际上面临着这些权衡。
you're actually confronting those trade-offs.
你必须找到一种真正具有竞争力的方法，
You have to find a way to actually be competitive
在某些情况下，真正引领行业，
to actually lead the industry  in some cases
但仍设法安全地做事。
and yet manage to do things safely.
如果你能做到的话
And if you can do that
你施加的引力是如此之大。
the gravitational pull you exert is so great.
有很多因素，
There's so many factors
从监管环境来看，
from the regulatory environment
对于那些想在不同地方工作的人，
to the kinds of people who wanna work at different places
甚至有时会听取客户的意见-
to  even sometimes  the views of customers-
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 那种朝着以下方向前进的动力
- That kind of drive in the direction of
如果你能证明你在安全方面做得很好
if you can show that you can do well on safety
在不牺牲竞争力的情况下，对吧，
without sacrificing competitiveness  right
如果你能找到这种双赢的方式
if you can find these kind of win-wins
然后其他人就会受到激励去做同样的事情。
then others are incentivized to do the same thing.
- 是的，我的意思是我认为这就是原因
- Yeah  I mean I think that's why
正确对待 RSP 等事情非常重要，
getting things like the RSP right is so important
因为我认为我们自己，
because I think that we ourselves
看到技术的发展方向，常常想，
seeing where the technology is headed  have often thought
“哦哇，我们需要非常小心这件事，”
"Oh wow  we need to be really careful of this thing "
但同时我们必须更加小心
but at the same time we have to be even more careful
不要哭狼来了，
not to be crying wolf
就像这样说：“创新需要就此停止。”
saying that like  "Innovation needs to stop here."
我们需要找到一种方法，让人工智能变得有用、创新、
We need to sort of find a way to make AI useful  innovative
让顾客高兴，
delightful for customers
但也要弄清楚真正的限制是什么
but also figure out what the constraints really have to be
我们可以支持，使系统安全，
that we can stand behind  that makes systems safe
以便其他人可能认为
so that it's possible for others to think that
他们也能做到，
they can do that too
他们可以成功，他们可以与我们竞争。
and they can succeed  they can compete with us.
- 我们不是注定的人，对吧？
- We're not doomers  right?
就像，我们想要建立积极的东西。
Like  we wanna build the positive thing.
- 是的。
- Yeah.
- 我们想要创造美好的事物。
- We wanna like build the good thing.
- 我们已经看到它在实践中发生了。
- And we've seen it happen in practice.
在我们推出 RSP 几个月后，
A few months after we came out with our RSP
三大最著名的人工智能公司都有一个，对吧？
the three most prominent AI companies had one  right?
可解释性研究，
Interpretability research
这是我们已经完成的另一个领域。
that's another area we've done it.
只是注重整体安全，
Just the focus on safety overall
比如与人工智能安全机构的合作，
like collaboration with the AI safety institutes
其他地区。
other areas.
- 是的，边疆红队几乎立刻就被克隆了，
- Yeah  the Frontier Red Team got cloned almost immediately
这很好。
which is good.
你希望所有的实验室都进行类似的测试，
You want all the labs to be testing for like
非常非常可怕的安全风险。
very  very security-scary risks.
- 出口安全带。
- Export the seat belts.
- 是的，完全正确。 - 嗯嗯，
- Yeah  exactly. - Mm-hmm
出口安全带。
export the seat belts.
嗯，杰克之前也提到过，
Well  Jack also mentioned it earlier
但客户也确实关心安全，对吧？
but customers also really care about safety  right?
客户不想要产生幻觉的模型。
Customers don't want models that are hallucinating.
他们不想要容易越狱的模型。
They don't want models that are easy to jailbreak.
他们想要有帮助且无害的模型，
They want models that are helpful and harmless
正确的？ - 是的。
right? - Yeah.
- 所以很多时候，
- And so a lot of the time
我们在客户电话中听到的是，
what we hear in customer calls is just
“我们和克劳德一起去，因为我们知道这样更安全。”
"We're going with Claude because we know it's safer."
我认为这也是一个巨大的市场影响，对吧，
I think that is also a huge market impact  right
因为我们有能力拥有模型
because our ability to have models
是值得信赖和可靠的，
that are trustworthy and reliable
这对市场压力很重要
that matters for the market pressure
它也给竞争对手带来了影响。
that it puts on competitors  too.
- 也许是为了解开达里奥所说的一些东西
- Maybe to unpack something that Dario said
再多一点，
a little bit more
我认为有这样的叙述或这样的想法
I think there's this narrative or this idea
这也许是善良的事情
that maybe the virtuous thing
几乎就像高贵的失败，对吧？
is to almost like nobly fail  right?
就好像你应该走一样
It's like you should go
和安全一样，
and like put safety
你应该去把东西放好
you should go and put things
你应该以一种不切实际的方式来展示
you should sort of demonstrate like in an impragmatic way
这样你就可以展示
so that you can sort of demonstrate
你对事业的纯洁性或类似的事情。
your purity to the cause or something like this.
我认为如果你这样做
And I think if you do that
这实际上是非常弄巧成拙的。
it's actually very self-defeating.
一方面，这意味着
For one thing  it means that
你将会有做出决定的人，
you're gonna have the people who are are deciding
做出决定，
making decisions
自我选择成为不在乎的人，
be self-selected for being people who don't care
对于那些不重视安全的人
and for people who aren't prioritizing safety
谁不关心它。
and who don't care about it.
我认为，另一方面，
And I think  on the other hand
如果你真的很努力地寻找路
if you try really hard to find the way
调整激励措施
to align the incentives
如果有艰难的决定，
and make it so that if there are hard decisions
它们发生在以下位置
they happen at the points where
有最强的力量去支持
there is the most force to go and support
做出正确的艰难决定，
making the correct hard decisions
在有最多证据的地方
and where there's the most evidence
然后你就可以开始触发这场争先恐后的比赛
then you can sort of start to trigger this race to the top
达里奥所描述的，
that Dario is describing
你知道，不是去那里，而是去拥有，
where instead of going and having  you know
关心的人被赶出了影响力，
the people who care get pushed out of influence
相反，你会拉着其他人去跟随。
you instead pull other people to have to go and follow.
- 那么你们都在兴奋什么
- So what are you all excited about
谈到我们下一步要做的事情是什么时候？
when it comes to the next things we'll be working on?
- 嗯，我认为有很多原因
- Well  I think there's a bunch of reasons
您可能会对可解释性感到兴奋。
you can be excited about interpretability.
其一显然是安全，
One is obviously safety
但我想我发现了另外一个
but there's another one that I think I find
在情感层面上，你知道，
at an emotional level  you know
对我来说同样令人兴奋或同样有意义，
equally exciting or equally meaningful to me
只是我认为神经网络很漂亮
which is just that I think neural networks are beautiful
我认为它们有很多美丽之处
and I think that there's a lot of beauty in them
我们没有看到。
that we don't see.
我们像对待这些黑匣子一样对待它们
We treat them like these black boxes that
我们对内部的东西不是特别感兴趣，
we're not particularly interested in the internal stuff
但当你开始观察它们的内部时
but when you start to go and look inside them
它们充满了令人惊叹、美丽的结构。
they're just full of amazing  beautiful structure.
你知道，这有点像人们研究生物学
You know  it's sort of like if people looked at biology
他们说，“你知道，进化真的很无聊。
and they were like  "You know  evolution is really boring.
这只是一件简单的事情，而且会持续很长时间，
It's just a simple thing that goes and runs for a long time
然后它创造了动物，”
and then it makes animals "
相反，就像
and like  instead
事实上，你知道，
it's like  actually  you know
进化产生的每一种动物，
each one of those animals that evolution produces
我认为，你知道，这是一个优化过程，
and I think that  you know  it's an optimization process
就像训练神经网络一样。
like training a neural network.
你知道，
You know
它们充满了令人难以置信的复杂性和结构，
they're full of incredible complexity and structure
我们有一整套人工生物学
and we have an entire sort of artificial biology
神经网络内部。
inside of neural networks.
如果你愿意深入了解它们，
If you're just willing to look inside them
这里有所有这些令人惊奇的东西。
there's all of this amazing stuff.
我认为我们才刚刚开始慢慢地解开它，
And I think that we're just starting to slowly unpack it
令人难以置信，里面有很多东西，
and it's incredible  and there's so much there
但我们在那里发现了很多东西。
but there's just so much we discovered there.
我们才刚刚开始破解它
We're just starting to crack it open
我认为这将是令人惊奇和美丽的。
and I think it's gonna be amazing and beautiful.
有时我想象，你知道，
And sometimes I imagine  you know
就像未来十年，
like a decade in the future
走进书店并购买，你知道，
walking into a bookstore and buying  you know
神经网络可解释性教科书
the textbook on neural network interpretability
或者实际上，就像神经网络的生物学一样，
or really  like  on the biology of neural networks
和那种野生的东西
and just the kind of wild things
那将在里面。
that are gonna be inside of it.
我认为在接下来的十年里
And I think that in the next decade
甚至在接下来的几年里，
in the next couple of years even
我们要开始进去
we're gonna go and start to go in
并真正发现所有这些事情。
and really discover all of those things.
这将是狂野和令人难以置信的。
And it's gonna be wild and incredible.
- 这也会很棒
- It's also gonna be great
你可以购买自己的教科书。
that you get to buy your own textbook.
- 只要把你的脸放在上面就可以了。
- Just have your face on it.
- 我的意思是，是的。
- I mean  yeah.
- 我很高兴几年前如果你这么说，
- I'm excited that a few years ago if you had said like
“政府将设立新机构
"Governments will set up new bodies
测试和评估人工智能系统
to test and evaluate AI systems
他们实际上会很有能力并且很优秀，”
and they will actually be competent and good "
你不会想到事情会是这样。
you would've not thought that was going to be the case.
但事情已经发生了
But it's happened
这有点像政府建造的
it's kind of like governments have built
这些新大使馆几乎
these new embassies  almost
应对这种新型技术
to deal with this new kind of class of technology
或者，比如克里斯研究的东西。
or  like  thing that Chris studies.
我很高兴看到它的发展方向。
And I'm just very excited to see where that goes.
我认为这实际上意味着我们有国家能力
I think it actually means that we have state capacity
为了应对这种社会转型，
to deal with this kind of societal transition
所以这不仅仅是公司。
so it's not just companies.
我很高兴能为此提供帮助。
And I'm excited to help with that.
- 我已经对此感到兴奋了，你知道，
- I'm already excited about this to  you know
今天在某种程度上，
to a certain extent today
但我认为只是想象一下未来的世界
but I think just imagining the future world
人工智能将为人们做什么
of what AI is going to be able to do for people
对此不可能不感到兴奋。
is it's impossible to not feel excited about that.
达里奥对此谈了很多，
Dario talks about this a lot
但我认为即使只是那种微光
but I think even just the sort of glimmers of
克劳德能够提供帮助，你知道，
Claude being able to help with  you know
疫苗开发和癌症研究
vaccine development and cancer research
和生物学研究
and biological research
很疯狂，就像，只是为了能够看看它现在能做什么，
is crazy  like  just to be able to watch what it can do now
但当我快进时，你知道，
but when I fast forward  you know
未来三年或未来五年，
three years in the future or five years in the future
想象克劳德实际上可以解决
imagining that Claude could actually solve
这么多的根本问题
so many of the fundamental problems
我们作为人类必须面对的。
that we just face as humans.
即使单从健康角度来看，
Even just from a health perspective alone
即使你把其他所有东西都拿出来
even if you sort of take everything else out
让我感觉真的很兴奋
feels really exciting to me
就像回想起
just like thinking back to
我的国际化发展时代。
my international development times.
如果克劳德负责的话那就太神奇了
It would be amazing if Claude was responsible for
帮助完成很多我想做的工作
helping to do a lot of the work that I was trying to do
当我25岁的时候，效率就低得多了。
a lot less effectively when I was  like  25.
- 我的意思是，我想同样，
- I mean  I guess similarly
我很高兴能够让克劳德工作起来。
I'm excited to build Claude for work.
就像，我很高兴能够让克劳德加入公司
Like  I'm excited to build Claude into the company
并进入世界各地的公司。
and into companies all over the world.
- 我想我很兴奋只是因为，我想，就我个人而言，
- I guess I'm excited just for  I guess like  personally
就像我很喜欢使用克劳德一样
like I like using Claude a lot
在上班，
at work
所以肯定是这样的
and so like  definitely
像在家一样的时光越来越多
there's been increasing amounts of like home times
像我一样，就像和克劳德聊天一样。
with like me just like chatting with Claude about stuff.
我认为最近最大的事情是代码-
I think the biggest recent thing has been code-
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 大约六个月前，
- Where like six months ago
我没有使用 Claude 来做任何编码工作。
I didn't use Claude to do any coding work.
喜欢，
Like
我们的团队并没有真正使用 Claude 进行编码，
our teams didn't really use Claude that much for coding
现在就像只是相位差。
and now it's like just phase difference.
比如，前一周我在 YCU 做了一次演讲，
Like  I gave a talk at YCU like week before last
一开始我只是问，
and at the beginning I just asked like
“好吧，现在这里有多少人使用 Claude 来编码？”
"Okay  so how many folks here use Claude for coding now?"
事实上 95% 的手-
And literally 95% of hands-
- 哇。 - 哇。
- Wow. - Wow.
- 就像，房间里所有的手，
- Like  all the hands in the room
这与原来完全不同
which just is totally different than how it was
四个月前或者什么的。
four months ago or whatever.
- 嗯嗯。 - 是的。
- Mm-hmm. - Yeah.
- 所以当我想到让我兴奋的事情时
- So when I think about what I'm excited about
我想到了一些地方，你知道，就像我之前说的，
I think about places where  you know  like I said before
那里有这种共识，再一次，
where there's this kind of consensus that  again
看似共识，
seems like consensus
似乎每个聪明人都这么认为
seems like what everyone wise thinks
然后它就破裂了，
and then it just kind of breaks
所以我认为这即将发生的地方
and so places where I think that's about to happen
但这还没有发生。
and it hasn't happened yet.
其中之一是可解释性。
One of them is interpretability.
我认为可解释性是关键
I think interpretability is both the key to
指导和制作安全的人工智能系统，
steering and making safe AI systems
我们即将明白，
and we're about to understand
可解释性包含关于
and interpretability contains insights about
智能优化问题
intelligent optimization problems
以及人类大脑如何运作。
and about how the human brain works.
我说过了，我真的不是在开玩笑，
I've said  and I'm really not joking
克里斯·奥拉将成为未来的诺贝尔医学奖获得者。
Chris Olah is gonna be a future Nobel Medicine Laureate.
- 哦，是的。
- Aw  yeah.
- 我是认真的。
- I'm serious.
我是认真的，
I'm serious
因为其中很多，
because a lot of these
我曾经是一名神经科学家
I used to be a neuroscientist
很多这样的心理疾病，
a lot of these mental illnesses
那些我们还没有弄清楚的，对吧，
the ones we haven't figured out  right
精神分裂症或情绪障碍，
schizophrenia or the mood disorders
我怀疑有一些更高级别的系统正在发生
I suspect there's some higher level system thing going on
很难理解那些有头脑的人
and that it's hard to make sense of those with brains
因为大脑太软了
because brains are so mushy
并且很难敞开心扉并与之互动。
and hard to open up and interact with.
神经网络不是这样的；
Neural nets are not like this;
它们并不是一个完美的类比，
they're not a perfect analogy
但随着时间的推移，它们将成为更好的类比。
but as time goes on  they will be a better analogy.
那是一个区域。
That's one area.
其次，与此相关的是，
Second is  related to that
我认为人工智能在生物学中的应用。
I think just the use of AI for biology.
生物学是一个极其困难的问题。
Biology is an incredibly difficult problem.
由于多种原因，人们仍然持怀疑态度。
People continue to be skeptical  for a number of reasons.
我认为这种共识正在开始被打破。
I think that consensus is starting to break.
我们看到了诺贝尔化学奖
We saw a Nobel Prize in chemistry
因 AlphaFold 获奖；非凡的成就。
awarded for AlphaFold; remarkable accomplishment.
我们应该尝试建造一些东西
We should be trying to build things
这可以帮助我们创建一百个 AlphaFold。
that can help us create a hundred AlphaFolds.
最后，利用人工智能加强民主。
And then finally  using AI to enhance democracy.
我们担心人工智能是否以错误的方式构建，
We worry about if AI is built in the wrong way
它可以成为威权主义的工具。
it can be a tool for authoritarianism.
人工智能如何成为自由和自决的工具？
How can AI be a tool for freedom and self-determination?
我认为其中一个比其他两个早，
I think that one is earlier than the other two
但这同样重要。
but it's gonna be just as important.
- 是的，我的意思是，我猜有两件事
- Yeah  I mean  I guess two things that
至少连接到你之前所说的，
at least connect to what you were saying earlier
我的意思是，一是我觉得人们经常加入 Anthropic
I mean  one is I feel like people frequently join Anthropic
因为他们有点像
because they're sort of
从科学角度来说，对人工智能真的很好奇
scientifically really curious about AI
然后有点被人工智能的进步所说服
and then kind of get convinced by AI progress
分享需求的愿景，
to sort of share the vision of the need
不只是为了进步技术，
not just to advance the technology
但要更深入地理解它
but to understand it more deeply
并确保其安全。
and to make sure that it's safe.
我觉得这实际上有点令人兴奋
And I feel like it's actually just sort of exciting
与你一起工作的人
to have people that you're working with
他们的愿景越来越一致
kind of more and more united in their vision
人工智能开发的样子
for both what AI development looks like
以及与之相关的责任感。
and the sort of sense of responsibility associated with it.
我觉得这样的事情已经发生了很多次
And I feel like that's been happening a lot
由于很多进步
due to a lot of advances
去年发生的事情，
that have happened in the last year
就像汤姆所说的那样。
like what Tom talked about.
另一个是，我的意思是，
Another is that  I mean
回到具体问题，
going back really to concrete problems
我觉得我们在人工智能安全方面做了很多工作
I feel like we've done a lot of work on AI safety
到目前为止。
up until this point.
很多确实很重要
A lot of it's really important
但我认为我们现在，随着最近的一些进展，
but I think we're now  with some recent developments
真正了解什么样的风险
really getting a glimmer of what kinds of risks
可能确实来自系统
might literally come about from systems
这是非常非常先进的——
that are very  very advanced-
- 嗯嗯。
- Mm-hmm.
- 以便我们可以调查和研究它们
- So that we can investigate and study them
直接具有可解释性，
directly with interpretability
与其他类型的安全机制，
with other kinds of safety mechanisms
并真正了解其中的风险
and really understand what the risks from
非常先进的人工智能可能看起来像。
very advanced AI might look like.
我认为这就是
And I think that that's something that is
真的会让我们进一步完成使命
really gonna allow us to sort of further the mission
以一种非常深入的科学、实证的方式。
in a really deeply scientific  empirical way.
所以我对接下来的六个月感到兴奋
And so I'm excited about sort of the next six months of
我们如何运用我们的理解
how we use our understanding of
先进系统可能会出现什么问题来表征
what can go wrong with advanced systems to characterize that
并弄清楚如何避免这些陷阱。
and figure out how to avoid those pitfalls.
- 完美的。
- Perfect.
鳍！ - 耶！
Fin! - Yay!
- 我们做到了！
- We did it!
- 哇！
- Woo!
- 好时光。 - 我知道。
- Good time. - I know.
我们必须更频繁地这样做。
We gotta do this more often.